Very warm welcome to the ICICI lumbar
general insurance company limited Q4 and
FY 2026 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Anand Singhi Chief Retail and
Government Mr. Giresh Nayak Chief
Enterprise AI and technology
Mr. Mr. Sep Gurada, Chief Corporate
Solutions International and Bank
assurance.
Mr. Gorav Aurora, Chief Commercial Lines
and Motor Underwriting and Claims
and Mr. Geresh Seagel, Chief Health UW
and claims customer service and
operations.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants lines
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchdown pole.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjiv Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you. Good evening to each one of
you. Thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ICS Lombard for
quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economic and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months coupled
with insights on a company's performance
and a key initiatives. Following that,
our CFO Gopal Valachan will take you
through the company's financial
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one. For the first two months, the
Indian economy exhibited continued
momentum of growth from the previous
quarter. Whereas the month of March 2026
has seen has been unprecedented in terms
of the geopolitical challenges. The
ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertaintity
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets. These external
risks could have some spillover effects
on the Indian economy warranting a
measured and watchful approach. That
being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress. This
provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks.
Although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions.
Let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by. Retail
sales of private cars, two wheelers and
tractors remained positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
WAN for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two wheeler
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently for H2 2026 the sales growth
of private car and two wheeler stood at
17.8 and 21.5 as against 4.6 and 3.2
respectively in H1 2026 led by GST
rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter 4 2026 wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheeler stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that two
wheeler sales surpassed surpassed the
their precoid peak and were at a decadal
high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle
based the data reported by WAN have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2 2026
versus 14.9%
for H1 2026 and a fullear growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digit for
quarter 4 2026 with broad-based
expansion across segments. Also, vehicle
vehicle financing continued to be an
important contributor to credit growth
broadly in line with the trends observed
in retail automoil sales.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come. Moving to the regulatory update.
You may be aware that IDA has mandated
insurers to prepare and present their
financial statements in accordance with
the applicable India effective 1st April
2026.
We view we view this as a positive step
as the enhanced disclosure requirements
under India's framework will
meaningfully improve transparency and
align the reporting standards of Indian
insurers with global practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both India
and Indian GAP for 2027 and 2028, it has
provided the insurer the option of
seeking forbearance through
transitioning the statutory accounting
to India for the first year. We've
examined the option provided by the
authority and believe it would be
appropriate to seek the forbearance in
order to ensure that the transition is
executed in a calibrated and oper
operationally robust manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiency, elevating customer service
and also enabling better risk selection
across ecosystem. We believe that over
time it will also enhance transparency,
strengthen trust and create enduring
benefit for the policy holder, insurers
and the broader financial system.
Let me not dwell upon the industry
performance for the year ended March
31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and marel segment, the
gross GDP growth stood at 13.3% for
2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 12.2% for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes, the business witnessed
elevated level of competitive intensity
and pricing pressure especially in the
fire segment in the second half of the
year leading to muted growth. The
renewals of April 1st, 2026 also are
being reported at a discount to the
previous year reflecting that this trend
is likely to continue for quarter 1 2027
as well. On the positive side, however,
we also would like to mention that the
in the reinsurance renewals for
financial year 2027 have been stopped.
The motor segment growth for the
industry stood at 9.2% 2% for financial
year 2026 with the momentum experience
post the GST rationalization the second
half of the year has witnessed improved
growth levels of 10 and a half with the
first half which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 15.4% for 2026 which makes it
the fastest growing segment for last
five years for from financial year 2022
to 2026. Within this the group has line
of business view at 12.8% for 2026
whereas the retail health g growth stood
at 19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2% in 9 month financial year 2025 to
119.3
in 9 month 2026. The overall combined
ratio for private players remained
relatively flattish for from triple 1.2%
for the period 9 month 2025 to triple
1.5%
for the period 9 month 2026. Due to fing
combined ratio for the motor line of
business continue to remain elevated at
128.1%
for 9 month 2026 with 123.8% for the
period ended 9 month 2025.
I will now proceed to present a
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in g domestic
premium income for 2026 compared to the
industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. ICS Lombard achieved a growth of
18.2% and 15.7% in quarter 4 and S2 2026
respectively against an industry growth
of 10.9 and 11.2% 2% over the same
period.
However, excluding the crop and market
segment, the company recorded a growth
of 10.2%
and for financial year 2026 by the
industry view at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as again compared to industry
growth of 12.2% 2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, a growth in commercial
lines stood at 6.5% versus industry
growth of 14.2%.
Bills for H2 2026, the growth level
stood at 3.8%
versus industry growth of 9.6%.
ADM amidst competitive pressure, we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious ris selection through our
multi- channelannel distribution. We
continue to maintain leadership position
in liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% for financial year 2026. As again
the industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026, we grew at 2.2%
in the motor segment versus the industry
growth which grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026, we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and a
half% in motor that is 12% with the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter 4
of financial year 2026 where we achieved
a growth of 15% with while the industry
grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private car, two
wheeler and combined and commercial
vehicles stood at 52.8 25.4 4 and 21.8%
respectively for financial year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a 1 byN basis.
For quarter 4 2026, the growth stood at
a robust 38.2%
as again the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail sales business continue to
demonstrate strong growth of 51.1%
for 2026 significantly outpacing the
industry growth of 19.9% in the same
period.
Consequently, our market share has
improved from 3.3% in financial year
2025 to 4.1% in financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a 2x
growth in the new retail health
indemnative business source. Compared to
the previous year, our share of
long-term premiums in new business for
retail health stands at 42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025. This
performance has been driven by on
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our real
health distribution franchise or retail
health uh distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025 with a
market share being 8.7% for financial
year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various line of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
year 2026 with financial year 2025.
A market share in advanced premium
excluding motor share stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026 up from 9.6%
from financial year 2025.
Our discipent focus on profitable growth
has helped us deliver consistent
outcomes over time. When market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters, our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value.
If we analyze the 10-year time horizon
from financial year 2020 2016 to 2025,
it is pertinent to note that the
company's average combined ratio stood
at 102.9%
reflecting sustained under
this would compare favor favorably with
the industry average of 115.3%
over the same period
has also remained strong. Over the same
10 year uh 10 year horizon, we delivered
a robust average realized yield of 8.7%
supported by food asset allocation and
effective capital management over
multiple cycles. This in turn has trans
return on equity of 19.1%
over the 10-year period which would
compare favorably against the industry
average ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution.
Our one and one team philosophy
continues to foster collaboration and
operational excellence
enabling a unified approach across the
organization.
As a part of this philosophy, we'll now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First, I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built in
house. one that materially strengthens
our execution engine. We call it IL1
Force.
IL1 Force is an enterprise productivity
platform which has been in operation for
over a year and is used by over 10,000
sales employees. It is on track to
become the single operating platform for
all our 15,000 employees across the
organization.
RL14 indicates work execution,
performance management, collaboration
and recognition into a single platform,
simplifying operations, reinforcing
execution, discipline, and driving
accountability with real time enterprise
wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management, and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle. Its renewal
capability has improved conversion by 5%
while enhanced engagement with while
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably in health indemnity improved
engagement led to a 2x increase in agent
activation and a doubling of new retail
business.
Our picture app, a one-stop solution for
insurance and wellness needs, achieved
21 million downloads as of 31st March
2026, reflecting the growing customer
engagement and digital adoption. The GWP
earned from the ILER app during the
period 2026 was 51 5170 million with the
corresponding premium earning for 2025
which stood at 2237.2
million. From a claim intimation
perspective, 67% of the customers now
intimate their health reimbursement
claims through the app while 82% of the
claim intimation of a travel product
Trip Secure Plus went through take care
app. We will continue to focus on
improving the service experience of a
customer with a single simplified
interface for their insurance
requirements. We continue to improve our
efficiency level in motor claims too.
Our preferred partner network service
75.5% of our nonoem claims for quarter 4
2026 respectively up from 74.1%
for quarter 4 2025. For 9 months we
recorded an NPS of 69 promoter claims.
In the retail segment 98.8% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days for
financial year 2026. For the 9 month
2026 on a count basis the number stood
at 99.9%
with the corresponding number for the
industry being at 82.1%.
For Ry one 2026 we recorded an NPS of 73
for health claims demonstrating strong
satisfaction level and reinforcing our
position as a customercentric
organization.
Sahayek has further strengthened our
onground claim supports for our health
customers and our customer coverage
improving by 25% over the previous year.
As a part of their feedback, 95% of our
customer survey rated their experience
as exemplary highlighting the support
provided during case processing and
assistance with hospital coordination.
These VAMS are focused on best-in-class
service to our customers during the
moment that truly matters.
The one call center initiative continues
to deliver strong momentum in the
company's transition toward the digital
first do-ityourself service model. In
March 2026, more than five lakh service
engagements, 69% of the total service
engagements were executed digitally. Our
differentiated service initiatives which
we have spoken about in previous
earnings calls have resulted in increase
of our call center NPS to 74 in quarter
4 2026 from 60 in quarter 1 2026.
Before I close the current year marks an
important milestone in the journey of IC
Lumbar. As we enter into our 25th year
of operations, we would like to take
this opportunity to express our
heartfelt gratitude to all our stake
stakeholders who have been truly who has
truly supported us in our journey so far
and we look forward to your continued
trust, encouragement and support in the
years ahead. I will now request Gupal to
take you through the financial numbers
for quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
Thanks Anjie and uh good evening to each
one of you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter in the
full financial year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers with effect from
October 1, 2024. Long-term products are
accounted on a 1 byN basis as mandated
by the regulator IID. Please refer our
investor presentation slide number 16
for the further details on comparison of
financials on a on an N and 1 by N
basis. It may be noted that all the
numbers that will be fixed 1 by N basis
unless otherwise mentioned
on combined ratio our combined ratio on
an N basis for FI26 was 102.4%.
That's against 102.6% 6% in FI2
for the current year was 103.4 as
against 102.8% in FI25
excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 35 billion. The combined ratio
for FI26 stood at 102.1%
and 103.1%
on N basis and 1 by N basis
respectively. Our command ratio on a n
basis for quarter 4 was 100.5
as against 102.1 in quarter 4 of 25. Our
combined ratio on a 1 by n basis for
quarter 4 current year was 1.2 as
against 102.5 in quarter 4 of last year
on investments.21
21 billion as at March 31 2026 up from
rupes 582.96 billion as at December 31
2025 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was at 3.48 times at March 31
and at 3.6 times as at December 31 2025
investment income was at rupees 47.42 42
billion in FI26 as against rupees 42.5
billion in FI25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion in Q4 this
year as against 8.77 billion in Q4 last
year. During the quarter under review,
the company has recognized we have a
policy on impairment of uh investment
assets. Uh basis that the company has
recognized an impairment on its equity
portfolio investments of rupees.49
49 billion in this quarter for FI26
versus a small ride back that we had of
almost about 3 crores uh that we had in
quarter 4 of uh the last financial year
driven by the prevailing market
correction. Now coming to profitability,
our profit before tax grew by 10.2% to
rupees 36.59 billion in FI26 as against
rupees 33.21 21 billion in FI25
excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees 0.55
billion the PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees
37.14 billion in FI26
our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FI26 as against rupees
6.68 68 billion in Q4 FI25
on the profit after tax. Therefore,
consequently on a 1 byN basis, the PAT
grew by 10.5% to rupees 27.72 billion in
FI26 as against rupees 25.08 billion in
FI25
basis grew by 12.2% to rupees 28.14
billion in FI26. On an end basis, PAT
grew by 14.1% to rupees 27.61 billion in
FI26 as against rupees 24.19 billion in
FI25.
On an end basis, excluding the impact of
the wage code, the PAD grew by 15.9% to
rupees 28.03 billion in FI26.
Our PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by 7.3% to
5.47 billion in Q4 this year as against
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 last year. same
numbers on an end basis pad grew by
15.6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FI26 as against 4.66 billion in Q4 FI
coming to return on average or ROE was
17.8% 8% in FI26 as against 19.1% in
FI25
excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion the roe stood at 18.1%
for FI26
ROE for quarter 4 current year was at
13.3%
as against 14.5% in Q4 FI25 coming to
dividend the board of directors of the
company has proposed a final dividend of
seven per share for FI26 this payment is
however subject to approval of shareold
ers in the encing general annual general
meeting of the company. The overall
dividend for FI26 including the above
proposed final dividend is rupees 13.5
per share. Last year the overall
dividend was rupees 12.5 per share. On
solveny we continue to exhibit a very
healthy solveny ratio of 2.67 times at
March 31st 2026 as against 2.69 69 at
December 31, 2025, which continues to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement. The solveny of course was
impacted by roughly about 14 basis
points as an outcome of the marktomarket
loss position that we had on the equity
book as that March 31, 2026. As I
conclude, I would like to state that we
are aligned with our ethos of driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are at the
forefront at all times. I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take questions that we may have.
Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchtone
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to please use handsets while
asking a question. Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now wait for a moment while the
question queue assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Supraim Data from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
you know um thanks a lot for the
opportunity. My first question is on the
competitive environment in the industry.
Uh there have been articles recently
indicating that competition in the
commercial lines have been fairly
elevated to indicated that you know the
motoral lines combined ratio remains
elevated. So if you could give us an
idea about you know how competitive
environment in the different segments is
panning out that would be helpful and is
there any improvement due to now uh the
um guidelines kicking in. So that's my
first question. The second question
coming to the loss ratio side uh this
year fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio
has been significantly lower than what
we have seen in the last uh years in uh
fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio. Just
wanted to understand you know what has
played out for this uh significant
improvement versus the run rate that we
have seen previously and why is the pop
loss ratio negative if you could give
some color on that. Lastly on IFRS Popal
you know would it be possible for you to
give us some understanding or clarity
regarding you know how your PAT under
IFRS would look versus the IGAP pat um
that would be very helpful. Thank you.
I'll take the second one first.
>> Maybe I can take the second and the
third and then maybe I can maybe Sanjiv
can uh respond the first one. Um I think
on the loss ratio super I think uh this
obviously comes to us every quarters and
I think our response will still remain
the same as in to say that one you have
to keep looking at motor as a category
as compared to one looking at separately
uh motor own damage and third party. So
that's one. Second, I think we would
continue to again request all of you to
keep looking at numbers more on uh full
year basis as compared to let's say any
given quarter and uh just to kind of
refresh what we have been telling the
street is I think the range that we are
comfortable on motor is between 65 to
67. I think that is the range that we
have maintained and if you have seen for
the full year current year I think we
ended at roughly about 66.3%.
it's well within that range and hence to
that extent I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely. Uh so in that sense there is
nothing that has kind of changed. Uh if
you ask us has has any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change the short
answer is no and we continue to kind of
maintain prudence uh in terms of
maintaining our uh loss reserves. So
hence uh I think we keep looking at
numbers more on full year basis as
compared to any given quarters. So
that's one crop. Uh I think again uh
time and again we have kind of talked
about it because generally again just to
kind of refresh most of the businesses
in crop get booked around quarter 2 and
somewhere around quarter 3 and maybe
early quarter four because those are
typically the two seasons that largely
get exhibited. In our case, we had
predominantly large exposure on crop
largely from one state of which a large
part of our premium was something that
had got kind of booked roughly around
quarter two of the year and as we have
said it obviously takes time for the
season to kind of play out in terms of
actual loss experiences and in any in
any quarter when you see that experience
play out then to that extent obviously
and if you recollect even at the time of
booking the uh policies we obviously
follow a very very conservative approach
of providing for almost 100% % loss
ratio at the time of writing the risk
and as the actual experiences play out
obviously to that extent in case if you
see some kind of a positive change then
to that extent that gets reflected again
in the given uh quarter and hence to
that extent is why possibly you are
seeing that number uh in line with the
loss ratio outcomes for quarter 4 here
again I would continue to urge that you
should again look at the numbers more on
a fullear basis on a full year basis is
pretty much kind of range bound whether
you look at FI25 or whether whether you
look FI26
um on India's I think uh uh in line with
what we had also kind of put out as a
part of the opening uh transcript um at
this point of time uh given the state at
uh which uh so one if you ask us is the
now now that is now there is a
definitive uh uh date uh in so far as uh
transitioning to India is concerned so
hence that's a very very welcome step in
so far as the overall uh industry is
concerned I think that's what rightfully
so the regulator has done
Um in terms of uh uh our own transition,
I think we do have uh we have been
working on a plan of action in terms of
getting our uh processes internally uh
up and ready so that we are able to kind
of start reporting uh numbers to all of
you uh uh whenever we are kind of ready
for it. Um at this point of time I think
we will continue to kind of give uh in
line with what we have done even in the
past we have been submitting performer
numbers uh for the last two years. So we
will continue even for 26 27 on a
quarterly basis in line with the
requirements we will continue to submit
uh India India's based results to the
regulator and maybe we will come back to
all of you at an appropriate time uh and
then we will possibly start talking
about more specifics in terms of the
impact that it does on both uh the
combined ratios and maybe the return on
equity objectives because those are the
two two things that the market obviously
kind of wants to hear from us. So we
will come back on that uh and maybe
point
>> so also you know the just to close out
the FRS part and we've always said in
the past also that uh the year of
adoption there would be a significant
decline combined ratio it can be in the
range of 300 basis to you know maybe 400
450 basis point but look that's only the
accounting part of it economic value
over a period of time it is expected to
converge and have the same you know uh
value creation for the company as it
happens. So, so our stance pretty much
remains same and yes from next quarter
one we would end up doing our submission
on that count. Uh with respect to super
on the competitive pressure that is
there and we spoke about that also when
we were giving the overall briefing for
the year that has gone by yes it has
intensified on commercial and business.
uh at the same time the the capacity
overall on the reinsurance side was very
high available and we've been able to
see to some extent it getting negated.
Uh will this continue? My my own belief
is market forces will play out but our
own understanding is when we see
intensive competition the selection has
to get sharper uh because it's will we
compete in the matches? Answer is yes.
uh but uh what we've been able to write
and what we will write we will be
creating differentiation if you remember
last year even in you know over quarters
we had said that there was a marginal
loss of uh market share for us on the
fire side purely was on account of the
fact that uh we will do what is
comfortable and the output is in some
ways here to see these are all very
exposure-driven products and you have to
be cautious of what you pick and what
you don't and we'll continue to follow
at uh there is no overarching worry. We
are very well placed as an institution
in terms of what practices we have to
counter any such measures that come up
in the market and overall insurance
general insurance in particular have
seen uh these kind of conduct at
multiple levels and we are well pleased
about it on motor also in a similar vein
uh yes the industry is been uh stretched
at multiple counts the command ratio
which I just spoke about for the 9
months stayed at 128 clearly not a
workable one We continue to pick and
choose uh and deliver uh uh a result
which is differentiated from the market.
It's purely led by on multiple count
distribution and underwriting practices
which differentiates in own damage as
well as third party which briefly you
know Gopal spoke about. Thank you.
>> Understood. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Pra Jen from Motila Losal.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Uh few questions on
my side. Firstly, if I you know just
wanted to take a view on your solvency
which is like uh very high at 2.7. How
do you think that you will uh whether
you because you've been generating good
profits over the past few years and in
fact from FI22 to FI25
and even now the solveny has been
increasing. So how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form or to kind of
because and unless the growth is really
exceptional we I'm sure that we wouldn't
need that kind of excess solveny on the
balance sheet that's question number one
second you know we've been talking about
motor TP price hike and uh you know
we've discussed this in the last call
last few calls as well but given the
trajectory under motor TP lot ratios at
about 63 3.2 in FI25 and 63.8 this year
for you. Do you think that uh you know
motor DP price hike can uh come in? Um
and my last question is on on the health
insurance point. Uh uh Gopal if you
could split up the loss ratios for
retail retail and group.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So maybe Yeah. Uh so uh so
pre uh uh so the first one I think uh um
I think as a company uh what we have
always maintained is uh uh sufficient uh
margins when it comes to solvency
because uh in uh the Indian market is
still on solveny one regulation I think
of course there is a road map to maybe
eventually transition to risk based
capital which again as what as what the
regulator has rightfully done on India
I'm
uh they would possibly try and do a
similar thing even on transition to risk
based capital as well. So obviously one
will have to wait and see how that plays
out but till that point of time I think
the Indian market continues to be guided
by solveny one uh which uh as I said
still mandates uh capital asks to be
maintained basis the gross exposures
that you have as an entity and hence to
that extent we have to be uh mindful of
and prudent uh in terms of the levels of
solveny that we carry as an institution.
Um having said that I think uh to your
point on uh the last few years I think u
fair observation but if you see I think
last couple of years in specific I think
we have been relatively uh lower uh when
it comes when it comes to growth but
that's something that we have already
seen a clear positive uh reversal of
trends emerging for us and with the
momentum that that we have kind of seen
in all fairness one would obviously want
to kind of make sure that we are able to
kind of get it extended uh even as we
head into FI27 and the moment you will
see as what you have seen uh let's say
even uh in the second half of this year
growth kind of coming back uh so to that
extent obviously one will uh look at
consuming some part of uh the solveny
that we have and three ours solveny is
also guided by obviously a mix of what
is it that we want to drive in terms of
the growth objective and two at the same
time make sure that we are kind of
appropriately kind of rewarding uh the
investors who have kind of obviously
placed faith in us and in that context I
think if you would have seen
historically we do have a board governed
uh dividend distribution policy in place
uh on an average I think what we have
been able to kind of distribute uh is
roughly about uh 25% of our PAT and this
year again as what we had kind of put
out in our opening transcript roughly
about 13 and a half rupees per share for
the full year roughly translates to
almost about 25% of for profit after
tax. Uh so hence it's obviously will be
a continued combination of both uh
rewarding the shareholders appropriately
and at the same time making sure that we
are able to use the capital for uh
growth and the three and the third part
as I said we will obviously kind of keep
a watch on the transition to risk based
capital. That's one. Uh to your point on
the breakup for the health loss ratio
numbers I think yeah thankfully this
time the question has come ahead of
time. So so maybe we'll answer it. Uh so
I think Q4 of last year this right now
I'll give you the numbers for quarter 4
employer employee book uh the last last
year Q4 the loss ratio was uh 98% and
this year that number is almost the same
at 981%.
on the retail uh indemnity book uh the
loss ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8
and this year quarter 4 the loss ratio
on the indemnity book is at 57.6
now the same year numbers on a full year
basis employer employee book for last
year has been at 97.2 2 and this year
full year the employer employee book
loss ratio stands at about 91.9
on the retail indemnity full year last
year was 67.9
this year full year is at about 64.6 six
uh so just therefore now to kind of
summit again on the indemnity book I
think the range that we have spoken
about is between 65 to 70% and that's
what we have been kind we've been kind
of largely talking through even in the
past several quarters and broadly if you
see the experience that one has seen the
good part is I think one we have been
able to book build a book uh which is
pretty much to our liking and it has
kind of played out both in terms of
growth in market share and also staying
within the loss ratio range so those are
the responses to the two questions maybe
the motor third party
>> so yes uh I think uh possibly it's been
almost 5 years now since the uh industry
has uh got a hike uh and the loss ratio
at the industry level as far as motor TP
is concerned is at around 85 and
thereabouts uh which is significantly
you know elevated uh where we are we
have been able to uh if you see and
Gopal briefly spoke talk about it. We
have to also reconfigure our portfolio
to get aligned and drive the efficiency
uh which we've been able to reflect. Uh
it does at time leads to a loss and
whenever we end up having discussions uh
whether individually or collectively
there's so much of you know questioning
as to why has the market share gone gone
up that is what it takes to reconsider.
uh we've also recalibrated our practice
in terms of ground surveillance and
doing what is required uh to avoid fraud
which probably we would easily say is
among the lowest in the industry.
There's no way we can claim to eliminate
it. So there are multiple factors that
go about it. We remain desirous of the
fact that yes the TP hike for the
industry is overdue and uh sooner than
later that should play out. uh but we
can only control what is in in our hand.
This one definitely is not. And in line
with that, we continue to forge our own
uh understanding and deliberation to
penetrate market at multiple counts and
make it work for us uh as a company and
uh from an industry standpoint sooner
than later we do hope the relief comes
through.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aventis Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity. Uh so so my my first
question is is that last year we we kind
of lost market share in commercial lines
um and um and given given the market is
soft as you highlighted. uh is it fair
to say that uh we we will claw back kind
of a market share in the soft market or
we will remain as cautious as we were
last time and and and in and and and in
in in these lines just wanted to
understand given given the soft market
growth outlook uh given given um your
second half growth is 16%age
uh and maybe crop being a new tendering
uh uh tendering uh year uh how do you
see growth of the 16 percentage to
continue for the next here uh and any
any color if you can give on that those
lines will be very useful that that's my
first question maybe maybe I will ask
another one later
>> okay no so no sit I think uh last year
uh I'm saying when you're saying last
year so year before the one which you
just given the result which is fin 25 we
were we didn't lose market share we had
gained by 0.1 we had a quarter here we
missed but overall we had gained we
talking about a market share which is in
the range of 13.7 which was year before
last this year we have closed by8.7
basis point lower uh and it's driven
through multiple configuration when we
meet up personally for I more than happy
to sit run through that uh these that
kind of a share that we draw these
fluctuations to ensure that we select
right can happen uh but uh the
commercial practice that we have is very
unique uh in the industry and it's not
driven by what business we're able to
write it's about how we are able to even
manage claims
uh there's a significant contribution on
large corporates to mid and to small.
Honestly speaking from an entity
standpoint we have been we have done a
much more uh uh you know recent job on
the large corporate side and over last
two to three years which we have been
briefing to you it's been a more
distributionled growth and we've been
able to diversify our port our portfolio
in a in a significant manner. We do we
do believe that uh we are we have a very
significant edge in the overall practice
and we will be able to uh have a you
know a reasonable presence as far as
commercial is concerned. I don't want to
jump the gun to say where the market
share will be but we will be a very
relevant player and it's not uh easy to
see us losing foothold on that on an
overarching basis. crop coming into
play. We will uh and yes the market
opens up significantly. We are still
awaiting the details in terms of on what
contours this market will open as in
when those guidelines come in. Uh we'll
be able to comment as to what it is but
we've always maintained our stand that
crop will be purely on selection. this
is of what we feel is appropriate rather
than a targeted segment where we say you
know that's not the way we look at it.
Uh do we want to participate? It's a
bold yes. Do we want to you know chase
it? The answer is no. Uh we we very well
placed overall to and we're excited
actually in terms of the opportunity
that will present itself. Our current
crop number is what was there year
before last or this year as virtually
half and uh uh there is some play
available for us to make it count in
this year.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sorry.
>> No, sorry. You're saying something. Go
ahead. Please go ahead.
>> No, no, sorry. Sorry. When I meant uh
April last year, you lost market share
in commercial lines because you believed
the market was too soft and and if you
are assuming it is too soft again maybe
maybe full year you caught it up but but
but given April is very strong in the
renewal for for uh fire whether whether
whether whether whether it will have any
implication in oneq growth or or April
growth which is which is significantly
very big and lastly
>> ah yeah go ahead lastly crop crop just
just wanted to add that uh whether
whether you confined till till last
three years to to one state um maybe I
don't know what final controls will be
but but it is fair to say that you you
will be expanding beyond a particular
state in in in the current year or not
broadly broadly that's that's way you
are strategically thinking in in those
lines or not is the point I wanted to
say
>> yeah yeah so so one state uh worked out
because it was in line of what you
wanted to do it is not a plan that will
continue to be a one state this we will
go uh wherever ever it makes uh you know
uh uh commercial sense and we believe
that it is appropriate and crop
obviously can play out the way it is we
are still awaiting structures. So there
is there is we are open to uh whatever
that comes up are we to be very honest
on that point and on the commercial part
in terms of uh uh what you were saying
look the growth of the industry itself
will get impacted and we are we are a
sub we are an offshoot of that. So uh uh
we can do better we can do worse
depending on how it pans out. uh uh but
overall if you remember in H1 uh we had
a
uh much bigger loss with what happened
in H2. So uh we've also done what is
required uh so what cannot get you know
like what cannot be acquired through uh
large corporates we have played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well entrenched uh so we
should be fine on the commercial part
also overall as an entity
>> understood so from growth point of view
given sorry to interrupt we request you
to please
>> no for growth on commercial because of
fire being there the industry itself may
have challenges is on growth. Uh let me
uh put this very clearly. Uh but it
doesn't mean that uh it put us at a
significant disadvantage as anybody
else. It would be probably single digit.
>> Sorry just to squeezing I was asking
that second half our growth was 16%age
though we did weak in first half. So
this 16% growth run rate uh you expect
to continue largely for 527.
there is there is so much happening all
around that uh uh how do we predict that
but yes Gopal mentioned that very
briefly we're very confident of moving
into the quarter one and quarter two on
a positive note overall as things stand
yes we but how does the industry play
out overall uh we will have to watch at
that uh uh we also presume that the the
the tailwind which got 300 of GST cut
which led to a very robust quarter four
uh would continue to play out definitely
we'll be well placed for a growth. We we
are excited with that opportunity but
we'll have to wait in terms of how the
market plays out. Yeah. Thank you.
>> Okay. Yeah. Thanks. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
>> Thanks for the opportunity sir. My
question is on motor. So in motor in H1
we grew lesser in the market in H2 we
grew faster in the market. So what drove
that and what is the outlook of our
growth with industry growth in FI27 on
in the motor segment.
>> Yeah. Okay. So Dish I think uh yes H2
was better there was also uh a
significant play that came out on
account of new sales uh for the country
doing better and uh there is no denial
in you know there's nothing which we can
say uh that we tend to do better when
new sales are uh very high and we have
seen that new grew at almost 18.8%
uh for us with 13.4 four on the own
side.
on the outlook of financial year 27. Um
we'll have to see we do expect a higher
singledigit growth at the industry level
and if that happens it would be again uh
good for us and other thing which worked
out last year was the growth of two
biller by by when I was talking I said
that it was at a decadal high in terms
of the overall uh growth that happened
we for last three four years we've been
saying that we have not beaten the
precoid number on two wheelers that
itself is again a big plus overall on
the uh motor I think the only thing that
I'll just add this just to what Sanji
was saying I think one of the thing
initiatives that we have also been
speaking in our earlier calls is our
relentless focus on improving retentions
uh and uh we will be very again happy to
kind of uh indicate that uh for the full
year I think at an aggregate let's say
company level a large part of which will
be predominantly let's say retail
business lines I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points
U so hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FI27. So that will be an
important lever uh that we would
obviously kind of uh uh work on uh
beyond of course the point that Sanjay
made in so far as new vehicle sales is
concerned.
>> Yeah. So basically the growth
acceleration that we have seen is a
function of growth new vehicle sales
going up and competitive intensity
reducing and we gaining market share on
a lack basis.
uh so yeah so new and old and I think
like this sometime in quarter one last
year that we had uh as a company
extensively worked on the retention part
a lot of work was done on multiple
counts uh by us and that's what Gopal is
referring to when he's saying that we
had a delta of higher retention of our
customers
>> sure so and that so should we expect
cube x2 trend to play out next year also
that we will grow faster than the
industry
uh are I think I think let me put it
this way we we will we are well placed
overall but uh there are multiple
factors see I mean if there is a there
is a challenge on the energy if the uh
if uh the Indian mentality moves into
the savings part of it rather than
spending the motor sales or auto sales
which probably all of you are well aware
of it actually ends up getting really
muted we'll have to see how that part
comes in uh but we would say that uh the
momentum on quarter 3 to quarter four
and so effectively in quarter one should
play out uh I would say yes we are going
with a very positive mindset at this
point of time.
>> Sure. Uh that's it for myself.
>> Thanks. Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh with MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh thanks for the opportunity.
Uh good evening. A couple of question.
First one uh a bit I would uh say if you
can uh clarify my understanding this 49
cr kind of a charge that you have taken
for diminish in value of investment uh
provisions in this quarter is it largely
driven by the equity for market fall or
bond or kind of a both so that's one and
second in motor TP of course you have
explained a lot of things uh my question
is that okay we have not seen a sort of
a price hike But what had I changed for
you that you have kind of accelerated
your growth in CV segment. Now typically
from whatever we hear it is a CV by and
large where the price revision is
required and it's not so profitable. But
in Q4 uh it seems that you have gone a
lot higher in terms of you know uh that
CV. So what had changed there? What kind
of a strategy is there? And for the full
year around 780 crores of motor park
reserve. Uh is that number I'm seeing
correctly? Thanks.
>> The last one.
>> So maybe I can take the last one. Uh so
Ain again again we will keep saying uh
you should keep looking at the loss
ratio range that we have spoken about
for motor as a category which is between
65 to 67. An absolute amount of uh
reserve number that you spoke about
honestly uh in our sense is something
that uh would not necessarily be a right
metric to kind of track. a better metric
will be to keep looking at the loss
ratio outcome which is the range that we
have kind of spoken about between 65 to
67. Now the good part is I think uh I
think what has worked for us I think is
I think we have seen a clear rebound of
growth and at the same time we have been
able to maintain the loss ratio
expectations that we have set out. uh so
hence to that extent I think uh is where
we have been able to deliver both on
growth as well as in so far as the loss
outcomes and that's something that we
are very very happy with and we are very
very positive uh when we kind of head
into uh FI 27 um and as I said uh in
response to the earlier question is
there any change in the thought process
of any of our reserving philosophies of
reserving processes absolutely no we
continue to maintain prudence we
continue to maintain margins
for any levels of uncertaintity that we
see in any of the books and more so in
the context of motor third party which
has got a long tail uh longtail periods
of loss development. So hence to that
extent uh that's in response to the
point on motor third party. uh to your
first point uh or to to the on the first
question with respect to the 49
crination in the value of investments. I
think this is what I kind of uh
mentioned even as a part of the opening
uh transcript. Uh we have a policy on
impairment of investments uh that we
kind of have in the context of uh equity
investment specifically and consequent
to what we have seen the market
conditions getting exhibited in quarter
four of this year. We have obviously
valuated stocks that we hold and bases
the policy that we have we have done an
impairment of about 49 crores. All of
this 49 crores is in with respect to the
policy on elimination in the value of
equity investments.
>> Yeah. Okay. So now on the uh CV growth I
think you're absolutely right. Uh it's
done better but there are you know
multiple moving parts. I don't want to
get into details. We can do it probably
when we meet a vinach uh and talk about
it. uh we've done better but the overall
contribution of CV to the book has still
been range more at 22%.
uh you see multiple you know things and
there's one more aspect that's the cost
of acquisition that comes into play and
if we see moderation we see an
opportunity we are also scanning the
market adding new vectors and something
looks viable we end up doing it we've
also created a significant edge with
with the market through a fleet
management system which we are working
for last almost uh you know 18 to 24
months and that has also started giving
us some bit of an advantage uh as to
what we can do in commercial vehicles
It's it's overarching it's still come
rangebound and we do believe that the
overall growth in CV market also for H2
was at a reasonable level which I've
given in the numbers in the details
which also again presented us with an
opportunity to do what is required. uh
overall on the practice side if you see
where ICS Lumbot is certainly private
car and two-heer is uh our you know our
strength but CV we continue to uh
exhibit uh a lot more intensity but the
outcome used to be moderate uh for us
and for last uh couple of quarters it's
come into play and I sincerely hope that
we'll have a similar trend going forward
next year or this year rather
Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nishan Chawat from Kot.
Please go ahead.
>> Hi. Uh this is slightly open-ended. uh
uh the regulator is uh you know looking
at uh uh you know newer set of
guidelines on commissions uh you know
probably capping commissions or
deferring them uh you know assuming that
you know this kind of leads to some
amount of tightening how do you see this
impact on the industry and for yourself
I think we've always maintained you know
uh an an environment with uh where the
regulator enforces it in the past also
we said that there are quite a few
players who have sought dispensation or
have not followed the guideline and that
does not occur well. Any tightening on a
uniform basis across the industry uh
would place ICS Lombard at a significant
advantage uh uh because we remain within
the limits of expense of management and
uh if others fall in place we can only
see uh better time ahead for us as an
industry. the the only thing that
remains is uh it should be practiced
across the industry at a uniform bas on
a uniform basis
>> and so it's a it's a welcome sign uh if
it comes out we always also mentioned
the fact that we believe the expense of
management should be on a single flare
basis so that there's clarity of
execution and let the market forces
decide as to what works for each one of
them every single business line
>> so so what is the latest in terms of you
know regulatory engagement on EOM. Is
there any revision expected around the
corner along with this separately?
>> We can we can only say that whatever is
accessed by each one of these what we
access and the we await for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second guessing but uh any
tightening on account of that would be
welcome by us because it puts the
industry in uh good path with respect to
policy holder and also for us as an
institution.
Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
ladies and gentlemen. We will take that
as our last question for today. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjie Mantri for closing comments.
Over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much for joining in. Uh we
look forward to the new financials with
renewed hope. We've definitely as a team
uh been excited as to how we've been
able to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4
over the rest of it. Uh we are positive
in terms of how things can work out for
general insurance industry at large and
with the reforms that the regulator has
put in place. Uh but at the same time we
hope that the the world moves to a in a
in a much more you know peaceful manner
in times to come. So thank you so much
and all the best to each one of you for
joining in. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you on behalf of ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your